I'll never give up this time!
這次我絕不放棄！
Ow, ouch…
嗚，好痛…
Are you all right, senpai?
前輩，你還好嗎？
See? I can still stand up!
你看，我還能站呢
He stood up using his broken leg!
他剛剛用骨折的腳站起來了
Well, if he insists.
唉，真是沒辦法
If you're in real trouble, I'm going to release the remote shield.
情況不妙的話 我會馬上啟動遠端護盾喔
Bring it on!
正合我意！
Ichikawa. Don't mind me. Just keep pushing.
市川，你別管我，盡管往前衝吧
We promised that whatever happens to me, you would…
我們約好了，我有什麼萬一就別管…
I'll support you. As much as possible. Let's go!
我會幫忙的，讓我們一起盡全力吧
Ichikawa…
市川…
Right. That's the kind of guy you are.
你就是這種人啊
If you say so!
你都這麼說的話…
Are they serious?
他們是認真的嗎？
Let's go, Ichikawa!
上吧，市川！
It's the unification plan!
進行合體作戰！
Everyone's looking at us! So embarrassing!
大家都盯著看，超丟臉的！
I leave the mobility powers to you.
移動就靠你了
Use the power from your suit as much as possible!
盡可能發揮戰鬥服的力量
My broken leg hurts like hell, but…
雖然我骨折超痛的
Please use all your knowledge to attack!
拜託前輩活用知識進行攻擊了
Yeah!
沒問題！
Let's let them in!
直接讓他們合格好不好？
-They'll be the official comedians! -Be serious!
-可以當搞笑專員 -請你認真點！
Chase after Kikoru, and don't mind me! Quickly!
不用顧慮我，快去追琪歌露
Got it!
我知道了
Don't fall, all right?
小心不要摔下去了
So fast!
好快！
-I'll beat you all! -See ya.
-我是第一名 -先走一步
Be prepared to support them as soon as we arrive!
追上之後就立刻準備支援
Leave it to me!
交給我吧
She won't even let us help, huh?
我們連支援的機會都沒有啊？
Number 2016
編號2016
has blown away the last yoju in Area Delta,
已打倒德爾塔區最後一隻餘獸
now engaging with the honju.
緊接著與主獸交戰
The last one…
最後一隻
Honju has been defeated.
擊敗主獸
Final round is now complete!
最終測驗…結束！
We'll be collecting the drones. Good work, all of you.
現在開始回收無人機，大家辛苦了
Seriously?
真的假的？
That was too fast, that bastard!
也太快了吧，那個渾蛋！
UNIFICATION RELEASED
（合體解除）
We're collecting the drones and taking in the injured applicants,
收回無人機同時救助傷者
right, Vice-Captain Hoshino?
是這樣沒錯吧？保科副隊長
Huh? Yeah, right.
咦？沒錯
That was way too quick.
這也未免太快了吧？
It took so long to get ready.
準備可是費了不少功夫呢
Kikoru Shinomiya. She's beyond her reputation.
比聽說的還厲害呢，四之宮琪歌露
Even she's interested in her, huh?
連隊長都對她有興趣了嗎？
We were expecting about 30 people to retire, but it's zero.
原本預計會淘汰30人的 但全都過關了
We have very few injuries.
傷者也控制在最低限度
This must be because Shinomiya was on the ground.
很明顯是因為她才有這個結果
As expected of Director General Shinomiya's daughter.
真不愧是四之宮長官的女兒
She'll be the future pillar of the Defense Force for sure.
她毫無疑問會是防衛隊的支柱
She's the light of hope for our country.
這個國家的希望之光
I was perfect,
我完美地完成了喔
right, Dad?
爸爸
All right.
好了
I'll go see Kafka Hibino lose for the fourth time.
拜見完日比野卡夫卡 第四次的糗態就回去吧
Kikoru Shinomiya's powers were superhuman,
跟傳說的一樣是個怪物
just like they all said.
四之宮琪歌露
Yeah. She kept crushing me good the whole day.
對啊，結果一直被她壓著打
But thanks to her, I was able to fight until the last moment.
但也多虧她，我才能撐到最後
-Now, we'll just wait for the results. -That's true.
-再來就等結果吧 -說的也是
What is that?
怎麼搞的？
What's going on?
發生什麼事？
Senpai, let's evacuate for now.
前輩，總之先去避難吧
I was able to protect my heart by concentrating the shield in one area.
將護盾集中在一點 總算是護住了心臟
I can still fight.
我還能戰鬥
What are you?
你這傢伙是什麼？
She's still moving?
還能動嗎？
He can speak?
這傢伙會說話？
What is that skin?
那個皮膚是什麼？
All right, now.
好乖…
-I'll leave it to you. -An intelligent kaiju?
-剩下的就交給你了 -明明是怪物卻有智慧？
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
You!
你這傢伙！
Don't forget to chew before swallowing.
別忘了要細嚼慢嚥喔
Emergency!
發生異常！
Number 2016 has abnormal vitals!
編號2016生命跡象出現異常！
What the hell is going on?
怎麼回事？發生什麼事了？
I don't know. But…
不知道，但是…
the dead kaiju are reacting. They're coming back to life.
應該死掉的怪獸又出現反應了
What? Those kaiju don't have that kind of power.
怎麼可能？ 那些怪獸應該沒有那種特性
Estimated fortitude measurement for the honju is complete! It's 6.4!
主獸推測規模出來了，是6.4！
Its strength went up? That's the level that requires a whole company.
強度上升了？ 這可是一個中隊才能處理的等級
If anyone here can take it down by themselves…
現在能夠單獨處理這種規模的人…
Release remote shields for all applicants.
啟動所有考生的遠端護盾
Yes, ma'am!
是！
Return the drones on the ground and display what's going on.
讓一部分無人機回去拍攝狀況
Hoshina. Let's go.
保科，出動了
…it would be her or me.
只有她和我了
Roger.
瞭解
Emergency, emergency.
發生緊急狀況
All applicants, evacuate immediately to your closest shelter.
所有考生請立即 前往最近的避難所避難
I repeat. All applicants, evacuate immediately
重複一次，所有考生請立即前往
to your closest shelter.
最近的避難所避難
Evacuate? But if we evacuate, this thing…
避難？去避難的話
Someone has to stop him
誰來阻止這傢伙？
or so many people would die!
誰知道會死多少人！
Use the kaiju muscle to stop the bleeding.
先用怪獸肌肉纖維將傷口止血
I can still move. I can still fight.
我還能動，還能戰鬥
I'll never allow victims, not while I'm on this ground!
在我的戰場上，不允許出現犧牲者
Be perfect, for the future of this country.
為了這個國家的未來，你要完美無缺
I have to be perfect!
我必須完美無缺啊！
I won't lose.
我不能輸
Wow, Kikoru-chan!
琪歌露好厲害！
KIKORU SHINOMIYA KAGARI TOJO
（四之宮琪歌露，東条明松）
Your name's at the very top! It means you were first, right?
名字排在最上面 就是代表第一名吧？
Exactly! It means I got accepted with the highest score!
沒錯，這叫做榜首喔
Wow!
好厲害！
-Lisa. -Dad!
-莉莎 -爸爸
Lisa, congratulations on your acceptance.
莉沙，恭喜你考上了
Don't pet me like that! It's embarrassing.
討厭，不要摸頭啦，很丟臉耶
-I'll buy you a treat, like you promised. -Really? Yay!
-我們照說好的去買賀禮吧 -真的？耶！
See you, Kikoru-chan!
琪歌露，再見
Let's go eat barbecue to celebrate!
為了獎勵你的努力，我們去吃燒肉吧
I told you we didn't need to worry. As expected of my son!
就說不用擔心了吧？不愧是我的兒子
Kikoru-sama.
琪歌露小姐
Master will be coming home today.
今天老爺會回家
I'm sure he'll be extremely proud.
他一定會為您感到開心的
Yeah!
嗯
You got accepted at the top of class? That's to be expected.
榜首？那是當然的吧
If you focus too much on one success, you'll end up tripping.
過於在意一次成功 會讓別人有可趁之機
Focus on your next goal.
馬上朝下一個目標前進
Kikoru.
琪歌露
Be perfect, for the future of this country.
為了這個國家的未來 你要保持完美無缺
For your dead mother as well.
這也是為了你過世的母親
Yes, sir.
是
I won't lose!
我不能輸
Don't stop moving forward.
不准停下腳步
I can keep fighting.
我還能戰鬥
You must be second to none.
讓其他人望塵莫及
As long as one arm can move…
只要還有一隻手能動
You must be formidable.
你要所向披靡
…I can still keep fighting!
我還能戰鬥
No…
怎麼會…
I've found the honju! Kikoru Shinomiya is injured nearby.
發現主獸，旁邊的 四之宮琪歌露受傷了
The attacking uniorgan that we removed from the honju has regrown.
本獸被事先切除的 攻擊性單器官再生了
Its energy is being compressed!
牠正在壓縮能量
Shit. Will we make it?
不妙，趕得上嗎？
I can't.
我已經…
I'm sorry, Dad.
對不起，爸爸
I couldn't be perfect.
我無法完美無缺
I'm sorry.
對不起
You did well, Kikoru!
你很努力了呢，琪歌露！
Why are you here?
為什麼你會在這裡？
Because you fought so hard,
多虧你努力戰鬥
everyone was able to evacuate.
大家才能順利避難
Now, leave it to me.
接下來就交給我吧
What was that explosion?
剛剛的爆炸是怎麼回事？
Shit!
可惡！
Come on. Keep up!
喂！別拖拖拉拉的
Run to the shelter, quickly!
快跑去避難所避難！
A signal flare?
信號彈？
-You can run over there, right? -Yeah.
-你們能跑到那裡吧？ -可以
Leading the evacuation, huh?
避難引導啊？
As expected of the JGSDF hopeful.
真不愧是自衛隊的明日之星
Kafka senpai.
卡夫卡前輩
Senpai, let's evacuate for now.
前輩，總之我們先去避難吧
The honju came back to life!
主獸復活了
Don't run there. Shinomiya's fighting it right now.
別往那裡跑，現在四之宮正在戰鬥
I alerted headquarters. Everyone, run. Those are orders.
我已經通知本部了 大家快逃，這是命令
You heard him, senpai.
前輩，你聽到了吧？
He's already gone!
竟然已經不見了！
He couldn't have transformed, could he?
難道…他不會想變身吧？
Could he?
不會吧？
If he transforms in this state, he'd be killed for sure.
在這種狀況變成怪獸的話 一定會被殺掉的
No. He'd do it.
不，他會變身
He's the type of guy to do it without pause.
他在這種時候絕不會猶豫
What is that?
那是怎樣？
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
You're…
你是…
a kaiju?
怪獸嗎？
Kikoru.
琪歌露
Please, please!
拜託！
Don't tell anyone at the Defense Force about this, please!
幫我保密不要告訴防衛隊，拜託！
Please!
拜託你
I'll fill you in on the details later.
我之後再跟你解釋
I'll crush him in seconds, so, relax and rest up.
我一秒就揍飛牠，你就放心休息吧
A mysterious high-energy source has appeared near the honju.
主獸附近出現不明的超高能量反應
It could be a new type of kaiju.
可能是新的怪獸
-A new type? -You have any footage?
-新怪獸？ -畫面呢？
The visibility is bad due to network obstruction from the explosion.
因為爆炸造成收訊不良 畫面難以辨識
What are these numbers?
這數值是怎麼回事？
Fortitude 9.8?
怪獸規模9.8？
No way. The explosion must have messed with the measuring tool.
怎麼可能？ 八成是爆炸衝擊害儀器故障吧
That must be it.
說…說得也是
It has to be. Otherwise, it would be a huge, history-changing kaiju!
若不是故障的話 那可是足以在歷史留名的大怪獸
Sorry. I don't have time right now.
不好意思，我趕時間
I'll clean you up…
看我一拳…
in one blow!
把你解體！
Let's see if you can resurrect this time!
能復活的話就試試看啊！
Huh?
咦？
What!? No way! Please don't resurrect!
咦？我亂說的，你還是不要復活啦！
Don't scare me like that!
別嚇我啊
What's with this guy?
這傢伙是怎麼回事？
Yoju?
餘獸？
Looks like you'll be all right.
看來你沒有生命危險
I'm glad you're okay!
幸好你沒事
Wait. But let me say this one thing.
但有句話我一定要說
You really should watch out for yourself a little more!
你最好多重視自己一點
That's my line to you!
你也是啦！
Hey, Ichikawa! Why are you here?
啊，市川，你怎麼也在這？
You ran out without talking to me
不跟我商量就跑出來
and you transformed and caused a big scene!
還不出所料地變身了
I thought I could get by with just transforming a part of my body,
我想說靠部分變身就能解決吧
but once I saw the real thing, I couldn't do it.
親眼看到才發現行不通
Just be more careful--
總之你應該更慎重…
Shinomiya!
四之宮！
Ashiro and Hoshina has arrived on the scene.
亞白、保科抵達現場
What's going on here? How do you leave behind a scene like this?
這是什麼情況？ 是什麼打倒方式才會…
This reminds me
這種狀況…
of something I've seen.
好像在哪裡…
Captain Ashiro, we didn't find any more applicants.
亞白隊長，沒有發現考生的蹤跡
This is the operation room.
這裡是作戰室
They took in three new applicants at Shelter Six.
第6避難所剛剛收容了三名考生
Kikoru Shinomiya, Reno Ichikawa,
四之宮琪歌露、市川雷諾
and Kafka Hibino. Three in total.
日比野卡夫卡，一共三名
So, they were all right.
還好他們平安無事
Now, all applicants have been taken in.
這樣一來，所有考生都避難完畢了
Roger.
瞭解
Kikoru Shinomiya is strong, but this scene is strange.
四之宮琪歌露很強，但也不至於如此
The resurrection of the kaiju,
怪獸的復活
this explosion site… There are a lot of mysteries.
還有這個爆炸現場，有太多疑點
Send out investigation and disposal teams.
叫調查班和處理班過來
Hoshina and I'll take care of the yoju.
我和保科去殲滅剩下的餘獸
Roger!
瞭解
It's similar to that scene three months ago.
太像了…三個月前的那天
Could they be related?
這之間有什麼關聯嗎？
I'm glad your injuries weren't as serious as we thought.
太好了，傷勢沒有想像中嚴重
Hospitalized again?
又要住院喔？
Shinomiya's injuries aren't life-threatening either.
四之宮似乎也沒有生命危險
They're using all the Defense Force's scientific abilities to treat her.
防衛隊正傾盡所有技術治療她
Why is she getting special treatment? I want that, too!
這差別是怎樣？ 也讓我去那裡治療啊！好痛！
You only have some broken bones.
前輩你只是骨折而已啊
It all ended in a blink of an eye.
結果一眨眼就結束了
Battling with those super talented guys brought it all back.
久違地和厲害的傢伙較量才想起來
Chasing dreams
所謂的追夢
is a priceless and precious thing.
就是做著最不能割捨的事情
It means losing to someone every minute and second.
卻每分每秒都有可能被別人超越
Senpai.
前輩
But it gets you fired up so much
不過，也能夠讓人熱血沸騰
that those things don't matter!
將那些事情拋諸腦後
I remember that now.
我終於想起來了
It's all because you pushed me to keep going. Thanks, Ichikawa.
多虧有你在背後推一把 謝謝你，市川
Captain Ashiro!
亞白隊長！
Why are you here, Captain?
隊長為什麼會來這裡？
I heard you two carried Shinomiya here.
聽說是你們把四之宮帶回來的
I thank you for your rescue.
謝謝你們救了她
Sorry to interrupt.
抱歉打擾了
Mi…
米…
No, now's not the time.
不，現在還不行
I'll talk to her once I'm an officer.
要和她搭話，等到我成為隊員再說
Just watch me,
等著看吧
Mina!
米娜
Dad. Was I perfect?
爸爸，我完美…
I…
我？
Dad?
爸？
It's fine, stay put.
沒關係，躺著吧
Vice Captain Hoshina.
保科副隊長
We took care of all the resurrected kaiju.
大家把復活的怪獸都解決了
And luckily, there were no victims.
幸好沒有任何人死亡
It's thanks to you, for cleaning up the honju.
多虧了你打倒主獸
Am I wrong?
我有說錯嗎？
I'm glad you're okay!
幸好你沒事
No. I was the one
沒錯，那隻怪獸…
that defeated that kaiju.
是我打倒的
KOKUBUNJI, TOKYO
（東京都，國分寺市）
Next up is the mysterious incident
防衛隊員測驗會場
of the resurrecting kaiju at the Defense Force examination hall.
發生怪獸復活的突發事件
Though there were few injuries,
雖然有多人負傷
there were zero fatalities.
但所幸沒有死者
-The kaiju that came back to life… -Zero?
-復活的怪獸… -零？
Zero?
零？
No way. Zero fatalities in a situation like that?
不，那種狀況下怎麼可能是零？
Is this "captain" person that strong?
“隊長”有那麼強嗎？
The search for Kaiju No. 8 is ongoing,
怪獸8號的搜索仍持續進行
-and the Neutralization Bureau is… -No. 8? What's that?
-討伐廳… -8號？那是什麼？
This is how you pick up a phone, right?
呃，接電話是這樣按，對吧？
Hey, where did you go off to?
喂，你跑到哪裡去了？
Break time is over!
休息時間都結束了
-Oh… -Don't "oh" me! Come on, dude!
-啊… -啊什麼啊？拜託你啊
Yes, I'll be back right away.
好，我馬上回去
Humans are so annoying about time, huh?
唉，人類對時間還真囉唆
Hey, I'm so sorry. I had an upset stomach.
哎呀，抱歉，我有點拉肚子
We were worried about you!
真是的，害我們很擔心啊
Let us know before camping out in the bathroom, okay?
要上廁所好歹先說一聲吧？新來的
Sorry, Toku-san.
抱歉，阿德
Apparently, there was an accident at the examination hall.
對了，聽說測驗會場出事了
Seriously?
真的嗎？
Are Kafka and Ichikawa okay?
卡夫卡和市川沒事吧？
Oops. Got to be careful.
哎呀，得小心一點
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻譯：唐詠傑